

# EBUKA UMEOKONKWO

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

Phone: +234 (0)803 - 2349 - 056

E-mail: ebukaume@gmail.com

Linkedin GitHub Portfolio

## **PROFILE**

I am a flexible software engineer with over 2 years of hands-on experience in writing testable, easily-maintainable and performant code. I hold a bachelor's degree in Electronics and Computer Engineering from Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka, Nigeria.

## **EXPERIENCE**

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

## Microverse Inc. California, USA. (Remote) (September 2019 - present)

- Provided 1:1 mentorship to 20+ students in both technical and professional capacities.
- Conducted 250+ in-depth code reviews on projects (both individual and collaborative) built in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, Rails and React for over 50+ students.
- Part of a team of 5 that review and improve code review guidelines.

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### Sky Tracker, Enugu, Nigeria. (April 2017 - February 2019)

- Worked with a team of 7 developers in an agile environment to develop and maintain several apps for company clients.
- Introduced code style guides and reviews into the workflow, thereby increasing code coherency and ease of maintenance.
- Technologies used in this job include: Node (Express.js), Rails, React.js, HTML, CSS/SASS, Bootstrap, Github.

# **SKILLS**

- Proficient with the use of Node.js (Express.js) and Ruby on Rails for creating REST APIs and with the use of React with Hooks/Redux in consuming APIs.
- Proficient with the use of ORMs like ActiveRecord and Mongoose.
- Good knowledge of the SOLID principles, OOP, BDD, SOA and ES6.
- Proficient with the use of version control tools like git, GitHub and Gitlab.
- Proficient with the use of RSpec, Capybara and Jest for testing.

# **EDUCATION**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT (REMOTE)

#### Microverse Inc. California, USA (March 2019 - November 2019)

- Learned the technical and soft skills required to work in a remote and international environment.
- Spent 1400+ hours working with other students from different parts of the world to build 47+ projects (individually and collaboratively) and solved 170+ coding challenges.

B.ENG ELECTRONICS AND COMPLITER ENGINEERING

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka, Nigeria. (October 2008 - August 2013)